{"test_questions": [[{"question": "Genetic variations are", "opta": "temporary", "optb": "influenced by the environment", "optc": "stable", "optd": "not heritable", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The mutation which will not affect the length of a protein is,", "opta": "nonsense mutation", "optb": "missense mutation", "optc": "frameshift mutation", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Changes in which of the following characterizes mutations?", "opta": "Phenotype", "optb": "Genotype", "optc": "Both (a) and (b)", "optd": "None of these", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following(s) is/are steps in excision repair mechanisms?", "opta": "Excision", "optb": "Incision", "optc": "Ligation", "optd": "All of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The whole-genome shotgun sequencing approach depends primarily on", "opta": "rapidly sequencing thousands of small randomly cloned fragments", "optb": "methodical sequencing a few large cloned fragments of DNA", "optc": "sequencing the bacterial chromosome while it is still intact", "optd": "all of the above", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What was the first eukaryotic chromosome to be sequenced?", "opta": "Yeast chromosome III", "optb": "Yeast chromosome XI", "optc": "Arabidopsis chromosome IV", "optd": "None of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following mutations arise without exposure to external agents?", "opta": "Spontaneous mutations", "optb": "Analogous mutations", "optc": "Induced mutations", "optd": "None of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Due to which of the following DNA repair mechanisms, one is able to distinguish newly synthesized DNA strands from older one?", "opta": "New strands do not contain cytosine bases", "optb": "New strands are lower in molecular size", "optc": "Old strands are methylated while new strands are not", "optd": "New strands are methylated while old strands are not", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following bacterial genome was sequenced first?", "opta": "E. coli", "optb": "S. pneumoniae", "optc": "H. influenzae", "optd": "S. thermophilus", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A nonsense mutation may result into", "opta": "an abnormal elongation of a polypeptide", "optb": "a large deletion within the reading frame of a gene", "optc": "a premature termination of the synthesis of a polypeptide", "optd": "modification of mRNA", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following mutation affects only a single nucleotide?", "opta": "Aerial mutation", "optb": "Site mutation", "optc": "Point mutation", "optd": "Regional mutation", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "When mutations involve vital functions so that the mutants are nonviable, it is a", "opta": "nonsense mutation", "optb": "lethal mutation", "optc": "transversion", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A mutagen is defined as", "opta": "an enzyme that repairs mutations", "optb": "a chemical or physical agent that induces mutations", "optc": "an inhibitor of gene modification", "optd": "a molecule which stabilizes DNA thus prevents mutations from occurring", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The DNA sequences of rRNA genes can be used to", "opta": "assess relatedness of eukaryotes but not prokaryotes", "optb": "obtain a tentative identification of a new microorganism", "optc": "predict the pulsed field gel pattern of a microorganism", "optd": "predict whether a bacteria will be gram-positive or gram-negative", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A nonsense mutation introduced into the DNA sequence of a gene may", "opta": "cause premature termination of the mRNA", "optb": "shorten the length of the protein encoded by the gene", "optc": "have no effect on the transcript or protein made", "optd": "cause a shift in reading frame", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of these mechanisms for thymine dimers repair lead to mutations?", "opta": "Excision repair", "optb": "Photoreactivation", "optc": "SOS repair", "optd": "Never leads to mutation", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Frame shift mutation may occur as a result of", "opta": "formation of a thymine-dimer", "optb": "deamination of cytosine to uracil", "optc": "conversion of guanine to xanthine", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Thymine dimers are directly repaired with the help of visible light by process known as", "opta": "phosphorylation", "optb": "excision repair", "optc": "photosynthesis", "optd": "photoreactivation", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The promoter on an expression vector used to overproduce proteins in bacteria is", "opta": "a bacterial promoter", "optb": "expressed both in bacteria and mammalian cells", "optc": "not a regulated promoter", "optd": "the natural promoter of the gene being cloned", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Differentiation of four different bases in automated sequencing systems is that each base has", "opta": "different radioactive tag", "optb": "cytosine at start", "optc": "unique antibody bound to it", "optd": "distinctive fluorescent tag", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}